<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title><![CDATA[ Young Green Party News ]]></title>
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/deleted/news-rss.rss</link>
<description/>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Green Party 2007</copyright>
<ttl>120</ttl>
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Can you design the new Young Greens logo ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/05/09/can-you-design-the-new-young-greens-logo/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>At the Young Greens convention our membership told us they would like to see a new Young Greens logo and we think you talented people are more than up to the job of making our new one!</p>
<p>It doesn't need to be anything revolutionary – simple is good, and we'd like to leave it mostly up to your imagination. All entries will be uploaded to our website <a href="http://my.greenparty.org.uk/sites/all/modules/civicrm/extern/url.php?u=14876&amp;qid=1039886">here</a>.</p>
<p>For a little guidance, the logo should:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be easy to replicate – fairly simple.</li>
<li>Work in colour and black and white.</li>
<li>Not be something that pigeon-holes us as environmentalists or into a particular political camp – it should encompass all our values.</li>
<li>Include our full name: 'Young Greens'.</li>
<li>Express some of the following adjectives: modern, radical, young, energetic, forward-thinking.</li>
<li>The logo can be just text, or can include an image/ shape.</li>
<li>You don't necessarily need to use it, but for information Green Party green is Pantone 368 and our fonts are TheSansOffice and TheSerifOffice. <a href="http://my.greenparty.org.uk/sites/all/modules/civicrm/extern/url.php?u=14877&amp;qid=1039886">More details here </a>if needed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Please email any submissions to <a href="mailto:admin@younggreens.org.uk">admin@younggreens.org.uk</a>. The deadline for responses is 31st May after which we will short-list based on the criteria above and ask you to vote for your favourite.<span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;"> </span></p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-05-09 12:16:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/05/09/can-you-design-the-new-young-greens-logo/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Young Greens Summer Gathering ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/05/14/young-greens-summer-gathering/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>This year we are hosting our first ever Young Greens Summer Gathering. We're going to be gathering one hundred Young Greens from Scotland, Ireland, England and Wales to host a fully funded five day event on Direct Democracy and Citizenship.</p>
<p id="yui_3_7_2_1_1367225099861_9530"><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1367225099861_9557"><img id="yui_3_7_2_1_1367225099861_9556" class="justifyleft" style="float: left; margin: 10px;" src="http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/files/splash.jpg" alt="YG summer gathering" width="250" /></span></p>
<p>This is a great chance take part in workshops and hear talks from expert speakers on Green issues, direct democracy, Europe and citizenship. There will also be socials, intercultural evenings and plenty of time to meet with, share experiences and build capacity between Young Green activists from Ireland, Scotland and England and Wales.</p>
<p>The event will be held between the 18th and 22nd of July 2013 in Gloucestershire and is financially supported by the Federation of Young European Greens. Food, accomodation and travel will all be covered.</p>
<p>If you think exploring and learning about these topics with other Young Green activists from the UK and Ireland sounds unbelievably amazing, you'll need to fill out a (short) application form and send it to <a href="mailto:admin@younggreens.org.uk">admin@younggreens.org.uk</a>. The deadline for this is the 17th May 2013.</p>
<p>The Summer Gathering preparation team in cooperation with respective Young Green Executive Committees will select the participants in late May 2013.</p>
<p>The form, conditions of application and lots more information can be found at <a title="http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/events/summercamp" href="http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/events/summercamp">http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/events/summercamp</a>.</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-05-01 15:56:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/05/14/young-greens-summer-gathering/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ It's election season! Join a Young Greens action weekend ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/04/10/its-election-season!-join-a-young-greens-action-weekend/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p><span>Election season is coming up and there are plenty of Young Greens standing. With less than a month to go, please get involved with a Young Green action weekend if you can and help us win more seats!</span><strong id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2060"><br /></strong><span><span><br /></span></span><strong><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2064">Bristol action weekend - 20th/21st April</span></strong></p>
<p><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2066">We are targetting three wards - one of which we have won before and two in which we are competitive. <span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2067">Rob Telford and Anna McMullen are both young Greens and are working hard to become city councillors. </span></span><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2069"><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2068">You can canvass or leaflet, all are welcome and we can find you somewhere to stay overnight.</span></span></p>
<p><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2070">We will all go somewhere together on the Saturday night and relive 2012's autumn conference!</span></p>
<p><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2071">If you're interested or want any more information, please contact Rob Telford at</span><a href="mailto:robertjessetelford@gmail.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><span><span>robertjessetelford@gmail.com</span></span></a></p>
<p><span><span> </span></span></p>
<p><strong>Norwich action weekend - 13th/14th April</strong><a href="mailto:robertjessetelford@gmail.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><br /></a><span><span><br /></span></span><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2072">Norwich is the second city for the Green Party and this May we're fighting six defences on the County Council and hoping to gain back a seat from a Tory defector. We've also got a by-election for a seat on the City Council which we hope to win. (Yes, it is always this busy around here). The elections are important in their own right, but we're also using them to build up towards the general election for which Norwich South is a national target constituency.</span></p>
<p><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2073">Saturday will be canvassing-based, with leafleting for people who don't want to canvass. Full training will be given for anyone who hasn't canvassed before, and we'll send you out with an experienced councillor or activist. In the evening we'll have a social event and a chance for you to meet councillors and activists in Norwich. On the Sunday we will put on some training on running election campaigns for anyone who wants it. We'll cover things like the principles of targeting, what to do at different points of the campaign and how to pick your issues for the electipn.</span></p>
<p><span>Contact Ash Haynes (</span><a href="mailto:ashlizhaynes@gmail.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ashlizhaynes@gmail.com</a><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2074">) if you want to come along and help get some Young Greens elected in Norwich as well as learning lots about the way elections are run!</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<p><strong>Oxford action weekend - 27/28th April</strong></p>
<p><span>Our Co-Chair Sam Coates is working hard to became a Councillor in Oxford! Fellow Young Green and 30 under 30 member Sam Hollick was elected easily in part of the ward last May but the County Council is being fought for under new boundaries. Previous results suggest the seat is going to be a close fight between Greens and Labour but if enough of us help out we can get Sam elected on 2 May.</span></p>
<p><span>If elected Sam wants to be a voice for public services and against the privitisation that the Tory County are all too keen to follow Cameron on. It will also be a big boost for the Oxford Greens to win this new seat to continue expanding in this very green city!</span></p>
<p><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2075">The ward is majority student but very diverse so you will get the chance to speak to students or local residents. We'll be doorknocking, talking to people on the street and leafleting for those who prefer it. We'll provide training before we start.</span></p>
<p><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2076">All Young Greens are warmly welcomed to our specially organised action weekend on the 27/28th April in Oxford. For more details contact </span><a id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2077" href="mailto:sam@younggreens.org.uk" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">sam@younggreens.org.uk</a><span> or join our </span><a href="http://my.greenparty.org.uk/sites/all/modules/civicrm/extern/url.php?u=14673&amp;qid=984584" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Facebook event</a><span>.</span></p>
<p><span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1365599272456_2078">We also have action days planned most weekends between now and the election, if you can help out another time do get in touch, we always have work that needs doing!</span></p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-04-10 13:35:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/04/10/its-election-season!-join-a-young-greens-action-weekend/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Young Green's Fund-raiser! Will Kaufman's "Woody Guthrie: Hard Times and Hard Travelin" ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/04/08/young-greens-fund-raiser!-will-kaufmans-woody-guthrie-hard-times-and-hard-travelin/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Will Kaufman's WOODY GUTHRIE: HARD TIMES AND HARD TRAVELIN' is a captivating "live documentary", with songs of Woody Guthrie played live and dramatised in the context of the American 1930s - the Dust Bowl, the Depression, the New Deal and the state of popular music itself.</p>
<p><img id="fbPhotoImage" class="fbPhotoImage img" src="http://sphotos-h.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/555692_549662735054896_2078184036_n.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="350" /></p>
<p>Such hard-hitting Guthrie songs as "Vigilante Man", "Pretty Boy Floyd" and "I Ain't Got No Home" are brought into conversation with other relevant songs - from Joe Hill's "The Preacher and the Slave" to "Brother, Can You Spare a Dime?". Altogether the show highlights the blending of music and radical politics that marks Guthrie's most powerful work.</p>
<p>Will Kaufman is a singer, multi-instrumentalist and Professor of American Literature and Culture at the University of Central Lancashire.  He is the author of Woody Guthrie, American Radical (2011).</p>
<p>The event will be on Friday 7th June 2013 at 7.30pm in London. For more details and to buy tickets, see<a href="http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/events">http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/events</a></p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-04-08 13:27:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/04/08/young-greens-fund-raiser!-will-kaufmans-woody-guthrie-hard-times-and-hard-travelin/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ We have a vacancy on the Young Greens committee and are looking for applicants! ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/21/we-have-a-vacancy-on-the-young-greens-committee-and-are-looking-for-applicants!/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Joining the committee is a great way to get more involved with the running of the Young Greens and to meet people who are committed to helping young people get involved in politics and making the future of the Green Party a young, and forward-looking one.</p>
<p>The Young Greens committee sets the direction of the organsation, helps to organise events, decide on campaigns, produce publications and decide on new projects. We hold a fortnightly Skype meeting and occasional face-to-face meetings in London (travel costs will be covered, and accommodation offered). The vacancy is in one of our six non-portfolio roles.</p>
<p><strong>General Committee Responsibilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Attend as many committee meetings as possible or give apologies</li>
<li>Take part in email discussion/votes on things that arise between meetings, where appropriate</li>
<li>Help promote the Young Greens at any event you attend as a committee member, such as conferences or student events</li>
<li>Help Young Green members with their work in local groups, student societies or individually where it relates to your role</li>
<li>Inform the co-chairs and/or coordinator if you are having difficulties with any part of your post or need help</li>
</ul>
<p>We are particularly looking for people who are interested in working on member support, but are mostly looking for anyone with enthusiasm and some time to offer. Other roles include Events, Campaigns, Press, Publications and International.</p>
<p><strong>Member Support responsibilities include</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Assist with Fresher's Fairs</li>
<li>Help new groups or societies in setting up</li>
<li>Develop recruitment strategies for local groups and nationally</li>
<li>Ensure Young Greens representation at NUS and other student events</li>
<li>Encourage sharing of ideas and good practice between groups</li>
<li>Work with Publications, Campaigns and Events coordinators to provide ideas and help to groups in these areas</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are interested please send statement (no longer than 300 words), explaining why you would like to join the committee and which area you would be interested in working in to Larissa at<a href="mailto:admin@younggreens.org.uk">admin@younggreens.org.uk</a>. Feel free to contact the same address with any questions about the role, no matter how small!</p>
<p>The deadline for applications is midday on Wednesday 3rd April. All applicants will be asked to briefly introduce themselves via Skype on 4th April between 9-10.30pm.</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-03-21 13:25:36</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/21/we-have-a-vacancy-on-the-young-greens-committee-and-are-looking-for-applicants!/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Greens Demand Representation in General Election Debates ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/08/greens-demand-representation-in-general-election-debates/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>The Young Greens have today launched a government epetition demanding that the Green Party of England and Wales be represented in the general election television debates.</p>
<p>The petition was sparked by a recent poll that indicated over half of Britons would want to see the party included on the platform.</p>
<p>The petition states “we feel it is right and in keeping with the democratic principles this country<br />upholds that a representative of the Green Party be invited to take part, broadening the debate and<br />presenting the electorate with a greater political spectrum with which to engage”.</p>
<p>Launched in August 2011, if government epetitions amass 100,000 signatures, the subject will be<br />considered for debate in parliament.</p>
<p>Press Officer of the Young Greens Lisa Camps commented:</p>
<p>“Voter turnout is dismal at the moment, but what do you expect when you can barely tell the difference between the three biggest parties? Including the Green Party in the debate will broaden what’s on offer to the electorate, and give the opportunity to consider alternative ideas.</p>
<p>“People are frustrated with the status quo, it’s time for a fresh approach to politics”.</p>
<p>The Green Party currently has an MP, two MEPs, 141 councillors and polled third in the London<br />Mayoral elections.</p>
<p>The epetition can be found at <a href="http://epetitions.direct.gov.uk/petitions/46764">http://epetitions.direct.gov.uk/petitions/46764</a></p>
<p>Press contact- Lisa Camps, 07792407420</p>
<p>The poll mentioned can be found at- <a href="http://www.angus-reid.com/polls/48600/britons-want-to-see-ukip-green-party-leaders-in-televised-debates/">http://www.angus-reid.com/polls/48600/britons-want-to-see-<br />ukip-green-party-leaders-in-televised-debates/</a></p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-03-08 16:16:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/08/greens-demand-representation-in-general-election-debates/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ 30 under 30 - Apply now! ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/06/30-under-30-apply-now!/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Applications for next intake now open</p>
<p>30 under 30 aims to discover the most promising young people in the Green Party and offer them training, mentoring and other experience within the political sphere. Our aim is for participants to emerge with the rounded base of skills and experience that could allow them to enter the world of politics at some point in the future. It doesn't matter if you're new to the Greens or experienced, or want to be Caroline Lucas or a press officer.</p>
<p>We offer five weekends a year of training for those who are successful, with travel and accommodation all fully funded. The weekends will cover a variety of areas of politics, including media, winning elections, policy and public engagement. We will also be going on a trip to Brussels to visit the European Parliament, again all fully funded (thanks to Jean Lambert). In addition, we offer everyone a mentor who is knowledgeable in the areas they're interested in.</p>
<p>The first weekend will be on the 1st and 2nd of June, and will be an induction weekend where everyone can meet and we do an introduction to the scheme. We will talk to everyone individually about their aims for the scheme and what kind of mentor they would like at this session, as well as inviting people from various parts of the party to come and talk about what they do. We'll also do a few icebreaker games and a couple of other introductory sessions.</p>
<p>The Brussels trip is 18th to 20th of June and will include a visit to the European Parliament, as well as other visits and activities to be confirmed. It's also a good social opportunity!</p>
<p>If you apply, you'll need to download the application form and diversity form and return it to Larissa (<a href="mailto:admin@younggreens.org.uk">admin@younggreens.org.uk</a>) by the 29th April. We'll let people know if they've been shortlisted for interview by the 1st May, and interviews will be via Skype on the 4th/5th May.</p>
<p><a href="http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/node/301">Find out what the first 15 on the scheme have been up to</a></p>
<p>Person Spec:</p>
<p>- Aged under 30 and a resident member of the Green Party of England and Wales<br />- Demonstrable commitment to the green party and its aims<br />- An interest in working with the Green Party, either internally or by becoming an elected member<br />- Some experience in politics or campaigning<br />- Willingness to learn new skills, contribute to Green Party campaigning, attend training weekends.</p>
<p><span>Download the </span><a href="assets/images/younggreen images/documents/30u30 application form - 2013.doc">application form</a><span>, </span><a href="assets/images/younggreen images/documents/equal opportunities form 2013.doc">equal opportunities</a><span> monitoring form and the </span><a href="assets/images/younggreen images/documents/Applying for 30 under 30.docx">guide to filling out the application</a><span>.</span></p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-03-06 14:07:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/06/30-under-30-apply-now!/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Young Greens go to Spring Conference 2013 - Crash Space Available! ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/01/20/young-greens-go-to-spring-conference-2013-crash-space-available!/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p><span class="text_exposed_show">This year the Green Party Conference will be held at the East Midlands Conference Centre in the bustling metropolis of Nottingham.</span></p>
<p>This event is a must attend for all Young Greens, whether seasoned or brand spanking new members!</p>
<p>Experience the heady scent of political debate in the air, learn something new at one of the fringes, lust after the attractive stall holders, exercise your right to vote and change Green Party policy or just come along to the pub to make some excellent new friends. What ever your cup of tea, this conference will provide an opportunity for maximum fun times!</p>
<p>CRASH SPACE is now available for Friday, Saturday and Sunday for just £5 per night! Please use the link to book your space, you MUST pay in advance - <a href="conference/crash-space-booking-form.html">http://greenparty.org.uk/conference/crash-space-booking-form.html</a></p>
<p>Please see the <a href="conference.html">Conference web pages</a> for more details or feel free to email <a href="mailto:admin@younggreens.org.uk">admin@younggreens.org.uk</a> with any questions.</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2013-01-20 14:00:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/01/20/young-greens-go-to-spring-conference-2013-crash-space-available!/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ An Alternative Autumn Statement 2012 ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/12/05/an-alternative-autumn-statement-2012/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>The Green Party is calling for positive economic policies instead of the Coalition’s dogmatic, self-perpetuating and failed “cut at all costs” approach.</p>
<p>Green Party leader Natalie Bennett said: “We reject this government’s self-defeating and contradictory approach of trying to cut its way to growth while providing tax giveaways to large corporations, including environmentally and socially destructive fossil fuel companies.</p>
<p>And we reject its inhuman and inhumane pressure on the poorest in society - households with members in work and those without - with non-pensioner benefits restricted to real-term decreases (below inflation, 1% increases) for the next three years. That’s £3.7bn being squeezed from people whose lives are often already insecure and desperate.</p>
<p>One certainty George Osborne has ensured is that the foodbank “industry” is going to become a permanent feature in Coalition Britain, the world’s seventh-wealthiest economy.”</p>
<p>“Britain needs to invest in environmentally-positive, jobs-creating policies, rather than using the UK’s historically unremarkable debt to GDP ratio to justify slashing state expenditure and further tax cuts for the wealthiest”, Ms Bennett said.</p>
<p>“A Green government would immediately invest the £4bn windfall from the 4G phone spectrum auction and the £35 billion quantitative easing surplus to create jobs in low-carbon infrastructure and in sectors such as renewable energy, energy-efficiency, low-carbon finance and manufacturing and in our contracting construction sector<a title="" href="file://sbs2003/Users/Visitor1/My%20Documents/Downloads/alternativebudget%20-%20LW%20edit,%20comments%20accepted%20(1).docx#_ftn1">[1]</a>. The Green New Deal group has called for green quantitative easing<a title="" href="file://sbs2003/Users/Visitor1/My%20Documents/Downloads/alternativebudget%20-%20LW%20edit,%20comments%20accepted%20(1).docx#_ftn2">[2]</a> to fund solar PV, insulation and other efficiency schemes that could create 140,000 jobs<a title="" href="file://sbs2003/Users/Visitor1/My%20Documents/Downloads/alternativebudget%20-%20LW%20edit,%20comments%20accepted%20(1).docx#_ftn3">[3]</a>.</p>
<p>“Despite Osborne’s best efforts to hold them back, green industries are already providing essential goods and services that we need - from insulation to clean power from wind turbines - having contributed over 9% of UK GDP in 2011<a title="" href="file://sbs2003/Users/Visitor1/My%20Documents/Downloads/alternativebudget%20-%20LW%20edit,%20comments%20accepted%20(1).docx#_ftn4">[4]</a> - yet they retain enormous job creation potential.”</p>
<p>The Green Party would  ‘reboot’ the tax system to ensure that wealthy individuals and multinational companies pay their fair share, levelling the playing field for small businesses that are currently paying their taxes and struggling to compete against the tax-avoiding business giants.</p>
<p>Ms Bennett said: “Our reformed tax system would replace council tax and business rates with a land value tax, a wealth tax<a title="" href="file://sbs2003/Users/Visitor1/My%20Documents/Downloads/alternativebudget%20-%20LW%20edit,%20comments%20accepted%20(1).docx#_edn1">[i]</a> to recover some of the gains from those who benefited from the boom years and have surfed unscathed through the bust. Furthermore, we would end tax relief on private pensions, putting the savings into a Citizens’ Pension that would immediately lift all pensioners out of poverty.<a title="" href="file://sbs2003/Users/Visitor1/My%20Documents/Downloads/alternativebudget%20-%20LW%20edit,%20comments%20accepted%20(1).docx#_edn2">[ii]</a></p>
<p>There'd be a financial transaction tax to discourage casino-style financial trading, moves to force transparency in the books of multinational corporations and a genuine, effective crackdown on tax avoidance.</p>
<p>And it is difficult to have faith in the Chancellor’s announcement of new infrastructure projects, as his government announced a similar scheme in 2010, which has actually delivered a decrease in spending on construction. The government has also delivered just £750m of a £5bn expenditure it promised for public works at last year’s Autumn Statement.”</p>
<p>Ms Bennett added: “In recreating the failed PFI schemes of the last Labour government, this government is repeating its predecessor’s mistakes and announcing headline projects that are unlikely to be delivered. According to the Office for National Statistics, we already have future PFI liabilities of £144bn. Renegotiations that have saved £2.5bn are small beer in comparison.”</p>
<p>“A Green government would provide genuine government investment in the new schools and transport infrastructure that we need. What we don’t need is spending on new roads, an action shown to simply move congestion from one place to another.”</p>
<p>ENDS</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-12-05 17:56:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/12/05/an-alternative-autumn-statement-2012/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Young Greens vote to support European Citizens Initiative for a Human Right to Water ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/15/european-citizens-initiative/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>At last weekend's national Convention Young Greens voted to support a campaign for a Human Right to Water. The campaign is being coordinated by the Federation of Young European Greens.<br /><br />The full text of the motion:<br /><br /><br /><strong>National Convention Notes:</strong><br /> <br />Since April 2012 One Million Citizens from at least 7 member states of the European Union can invite the European Commission to start a legislative proposal on a certain topic. This procedure is called European Citizens Initiative (ECI).<br /> <br />The European Citizens Initiative 'Water and Sanitation are a human right! Water is a public good, not a commodity.' has been launched in May 2012. Concrete demands of the initiative are:<br /> <br />“We invite the European Commission to propose legislation implementing the human right to water and sanitation as recognised by the United Nations, and promoting the provision of water and sanitation as essential public services for all. The EU legislation should require governments to ensure and to provide all citizens with sufficient and clean drinking water and sanitation. We urge that:<br /><br /></p>
<ol>
<li>The EU institutions and Member States be obliged to ensure that all inhabitants enjoy the right to water and sanitation.</li>
<li>Water supply and management of water resources not be subject to ‘internal market rules’ and that water services are excluded from liberalisation.</li>
<li>The EU increases its efforts to achieve universal access to water and sanitation.”</li>
</ol>
<p><br />Between the launched initiatives the water initiative of the European Public Service Union and many other NGOs is the best organized one.<br /> <br />The Federation of Young European Greens (FYEG) developed a strategy for promoting ECIs. In order to promote an ECI, FYEG needs 10 Member Organisations on their side to officially support a campaign.<br /> <br /><br /><strong>National Convention Believes:</strong> </p>
<ol>
<li>European Democracy should be improved.</li>
<li>The European Citizens Initiative is not binding on the Commission, but still more than a petition. An infrastructure is provided to build up European Networks of Citizens. People need to work together across borders. This is the first step towards bottom-up Democratic reforms.</li>
<li>Access to Water and Sanitation should be guaranteed for everybody in Europe and the world.</li>
<li>Liberalisation of water leads to a poor infrastructure and high prices.</li>
</ol>
<p> <br /><strong>National Convention Resolves:</strong><br /> </p>
<ol>
<li>YGs support the European Citizens Initiative 'Water and Sanitation are a human right! Water is a public good, not a commodity.'</li>
<li>YGs take part in the FYEG campaign to promote the ECI 'Water and Sanitation are a human right! Water is a public good, not a commodity.'</li>
<li>YGs nominate a contact person for the FYEG campaign.</li>
<li>Efforts should be made to collect signatures for the campaign.</li>
</ol> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-11-15 16:08:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/15/european-citizens-initiative/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ New National Committee Elected ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/15/new-national-committee-elected/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Last weekend at our annual Convention members voted for a new National Committee. The results are as follows:<br /><br /><strong>Female co-chair:</strong> Ash Haynes<br /><br /><strong>Male co-chair:</strong> Sam Coates<br /><br /><strong>Treasurer:</strong> Charlene Conception<br /><br /><strong>Non-portfolio positions:</strong><br /><br />Lisa Camps<br /><br />Juliette Daigre<br /><br />Robert Eagleton<br /><br />Ellie Ferguson<br /><br />Siobhan MacMahon<br /><br />Rustam Majainah<br /><br />Thanks to everyone who stood and congratulations to those elected.</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-11-02 15:48:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/15/new-national-committee-elected/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Convention votes for economic democracy and housing justice ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/02/convention-votes-for-economic-democracy-and-housing-justice/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Sam Coates, male co-chair said:</p>
<p>"I'm really pleased that we've voted to put these two issues centre stage. The toxic cocktail of high youth unemployment and lack of access to decent, affordable housing is affecting so many young people and the policy we passed in Sheffield is a response that fits the bill."</p>
<p>The full papers are below.</p>
<p> </p>
<h1 class="pageTitle">Towards Economic Democracy</h1>
<p> </p>
<p>This policy paper was passed at Young Greens Convention 2012 in Sheffield. The original text is adapted from articles by Peter Tatchel.</p>
<p>Currently most economic decision-making is concentrated in the hands of a tiny, privileged cabal of major shareholders, directors and managers. Whatever people think of the current economic system, one thing is indisputable: it is characterised by an absence of democracy, participation, transparency and accountability. Employees and their representative bodies - the trade unions - are frozen out of economic influence and decision-making.</p>
<p>It is time to bring the economy into democratic alignment with the political system. Extending the economic franchise is about democracy and justice. It can help create a greater plurality and diversity of economic power, and also lay the foundations for a more equitable and productive economic partnership between all those who contribute to wealth creation and to the provision of public and private services.<span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;"> </span></p>
<p>There are several ways in which we could begin this structural democratisation and cooperativisation of the economy. We propose to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Asserting and retaining public control of the banks that were rescued by the government, to ensure that they operate in the public interest and use their future profits for the public good. Retaining public control or remutualising the banks could be the means to fund new social housing and low-interest loans to poorer families; as well as a means to finance employee-owned cooperative enterprises.</li>
<li>Make corporate negligence and recklessness an explicit criminal offence, to reign in big business sharks and ensure more responsible economic management. Bankers and company bosses should not be able to wreck whole economies and squander with impunity people’s jobs, pensions and savings. They ought to be personally liable for damaging corporate decisions, in the same way that doctors and others can be held liable for professional negligence. The threat of legal penalties is likely to result in more prudent corporate governance.</li>
<li>Legally limit corporate bonuses to a weighted percentage taken from a minimum of 4 years future profit. This could be payable in a combination of shares, money and paid leave (with a minimum of 20% each). If the individual has left the organisation, they will be paid their leave's worth at salary rate, of the year in question. This would deter short-term, high-risk investments. It would make bonuses conditional on a business’s long term success. Only people who made successful, sustainable investment decisions would be rewarded. There should be no automatic bonuses.</li>
<li>Implement a system of industrial democracy which would require the boards of all public and private enterprises with 50 or more employees to establish equal representation and joint control between management and elected staff representatives. Under an independent chairperson acceptable to both sides, these boards would have full access to all corporate information and the final say over all corporate decisions, including investment, technology, wages, prices and so on. Although imperfect, this system of co-determination would produce a major extension in workplace democracy. It would shift the balance of economic power; constraining the remit of capital and expanding the influence of labour; forging a more co-equal partnership. It would also be good for the economy because worker directors would offer independent oversight of corporate operations and bring to the boardroom practical, often cost-saving, insights from their direct day-to-day experience. Not motivated by the profit motive and private gain, they would be more likely to blow the whistle on reckless risk-taking and on decisions that damage the consumer and the environment.</li>
<li>Enable trade union, in combination with the state, control of pension funds. This could be accomplished by legislatively re-assigning the administration of pension fund assets to potential experts appointed by, and accountable to, individual trade unions, as well as the state, who would act as trustees of the funds on behalf of their members all across the country. Or, alternatively the funds could be placed in the hands of a regional union pension funds, overlooked by the state, acting for all the trade unions and their members in a particular region. This would localise and decentralise investment capital. It could then direct these funds in to specific enterprises corresponding to the interests of union members and to broader social needs, such as the development of renewable energy and conversion of arms industries to socially useful civilian manufacture. The states co-regulation would ensure diversification of investment while preventing self interest.</li>
<li><a name="_GoBack"></a>Give employees the legal right to buy-out their companies and turn them into workers cooperatives contingent on them following green and ethical policies. Buy outs could be funded with loans from publicly-controlled banks. This would weaken the power of big corporations, localise and socialise economic decision-making and give employees incentives for greater productivity. Evidence shows that people employed in workers cooperatives often have higher output, better job satisfaction and stronger social solidarity.</li>
<li>Progressively transfer share ownership into trade union-administered employee share funds. This would obligate all private share capital companies to assign to a union-controlled fund a proportion of their annual profits in the form of a new share issue. This would gradually, over many decades, give employees, through their unions, a controlling interest in their firms - transforming them into self-governing workers’ co-operatives.</li>
</ul>
<p>In contrast to traditional reformist economic doctrines of Keynesianism and Welfare Statism, which merely seek to redistribute wealth more fairly within the confines of the existing free market, private ownership, bosses-rule system, these ideas for economic democracy are mechanisms for the structural transformation of capitalism. If implemented, they would alter, fundamentally, the distribution of wealth and power, in favour of organised labour and working people.</p>
<p>A new left revival requires new thinking. We need to make the left relevant again by offering both radical and practical solutions to the economic crisis – a crisis that has arisen, in large part, from concentrated and unaccountable economic power. This means challenging the system of economic dictatorship and setting out a new model of economic participation, accountability, decentralisation and transparency. The interests of employees, consumers and the wider public welfare demand it. The time for economic democracy is now.</p>
<p> </p>
<h1 class="pageTitle">Housing Policy</h1>
<p> </p>
<p>Young people are facing massive challenges with housing. Access to housing for young people in all sectors is collapsing. This means young people are staying at home far longer than before, and substantially restricts their freedom to make choices to shape their lives.</p>
<p>Part of this problem is due to the rising price of housing in the private sector and a lack of new social housing. Similarly, the impact of the credit crunch means that it is more difficult for young people to own housing, which has been the goal of Labour and Conservative governments for the past 30 years.</p>
<p>Unemployment and benefits cuts to those in and out of work mean that those with housing are finding it difficult to afford to stay there. With youth unemployment (16-24) at over 1 million (20%) and housing benefit being systematically cut, the current generation is falling into a deep housing crisis.</p>
<p>Prior to the financial crisis and recession, young people were expected to move into private rented housing and from there into more secure social housing or to buy their own home. Young Greens believe that housing is a right and that access to quality, affordable, and secure housing can best me met through a more balanced mix of housing than present.</p>
<p>The role of housing and of the reckless promotion and financing of home ownership through sub-prime mortgages is well known. The UK has one of the highest proportions of ownership (69% )after Greece (93%), Spain (86%), and Ireland (73%). Whereas Denmark, Sweden and Germany have a more or less similar proportion of rented and owned housing (approx. 40%).</p>
<p>As Young Greens, we also believe that all housing should be brought up to decent standards. This means that new housing should be built to high environmental standards, which would mean lower fuel costs and better health for tenants. This principle should also be extended into existing private rented housing, by setting higher and rising standards and government investing in improvement.</p>
<p>A more sustainable and just housing deal for young people could be achieved with the following steps:</p>
<ul>
<li>Oppose the Welfare Reform Bill and the cutting of housing benefit to under 25s, many of whom have dependent children. These changes will increase youth homelessness and restrict access to housing</li>
<li>Oppose massive subsidies directed towards encouraging home ownership. Support a more balanced and stable housing sector by building new social council and cooperative housing</li>
<li>Protect private tenants by regulating lettings agents, and the rents they charge. Shelter have recently proposed the creation of a stable rent contract which would control rents, and we endorse this proposal.</li>
<li>Protect existing social housing by ending the right to buy, opposing deregulation of social housing, and the privatisation of Housing Associations.</li>
<li>Repeal the criminalisation of squatting – homeless people should not be criminalised if adequate housing cannot be provided through social security.</li>
<li>Raise the energy standards of new build homes and extend the Decent Homes Standard into private rented housing and fund improvements.</li>
<li>We would levy extra taxes on empty homes, and encourage those who are under-occupying housing to transition into more suitable housing.</li>
<li>Repeal reduced tenure for new social housing contracts as passed under 2011 Localism act. Oppose the bedroom tax.</li>
</ul>
<p>The role of activism in housing is crucial. The Young Greens aim to get involved in campaigns to improve housing locally and nationally. This could be in the form of setting up new campaign groups in local areas or supporting existing struggles. The Young Greens are committed to campaigning for socially just and environmentally sustainable housing inside and outside of parliament.</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-11-02 13:45:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/02/convention-votes-for-economic-democracy-and-housing-justice/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Young Greens vote to support European Citizens Initiative for a Human Right to Water ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/31/european-citizens-initiative-water/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>At last weekend's national Convention Young Greens voted to support a campaign for a Human Right to Water. The campaign is being coordinated by the Federation of Young European Greens.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">The full text of the motion</span></p>
<p>National Convention Notes:</p>
<p>Since April 2012 One Million Citizens from at least 7 member states of the European Union can invite the European Commission to start a legislative proposal on a certain topic. This procedure is called European Citizens Initiative (ECI).</p>
<p>The European Citizens Initiative 'Water and Sanitation are a human right! Water is a public good, not a commodity.' has been launched in May 2012. Concrete demands of the initiative are:</p>
<p>"We invite the European Commission to propose legislation implementing the human right to water and sanitation as recognised by the United Nations, and promoting the provision of water and sanitation as essential public services for all. The EU legislation should require governments to ensure and to provide all citizens with sufficient and clean drinking water and sanitation. We urge that:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">The EU institutions and Member States be obliged to ensure that all inhabitants enjoy the right to water and sanitation.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">Water supply and management of water resources not be subject to 'internal market rules' and that water services are excluded from liberalisation.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">The EU increases its efforts to achieve universal access to water and sanitation."</span></li>
</ol>
<p>Between the launched initiatives the water initiative of the European Public Service Union and many other NGOs is the best organized one.</p>
<p>The Federation of Young European Greens (FYEG) developed a strategy for promoting ECIs. In order to promote an ECI, FYEG needs 10 Member Organisations on their side to officially support a campaign.</p>
<p>National Convention Believes:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">European Democracy should be improved.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">The European Citizens Initiative is not binding on the Commission, but still more than a petition. An infrastructure is provided to build up European Networks of Citizens. People need to work together across borders. This is the first step towards bottom-up Democratic reforms.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">Access to Water and Sanitation should be guaranteed for everybody in Europe and the world.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">Liberalisation of water leads to a poor infrastructure and high prices.</span></li>
</ol>
<p>National Convention Resolves:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">YGs support the European Citizens Initiative 'Water and Sanitation are a human right! Water is a public good, not a commodity.'</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">YGs take part in the FYEG campaign to promote the ECI 'Water and Sanitation are a human right! Water is a public good, not a commodity.'</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">YGs nominate a contact person for the FYEG campaign.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 1.2em; line-height: 1.6em;">Efforts should be made to collect signatures for the campaign.</span></li>
</ol> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-10-31 14:45:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/31/european-citizens-initiative-water/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Convention votes for economic democracy and housing justice ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/15/convention-votes-for-economic-democracy-and-housing-justice/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Young Greens Convention has voted to adopt our first ever policy platforms, passing papers on Economic Democracy and Housing.<br /><br />Sam Coates, male co-chair said:<br /><br />"I'm really pleased that we've voted to put these two issues centre stage. The toxic cocktail of high youth unemployment and lack of access to decent, affordable housing is affecting so many young people and the policy we passed in Sheffield is a response that fits the bill."<br /><br />View the full papers on <a href="http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/convention2012/policy/economicdemocracy">Economic Democracy</a> or <a href="http://younggreens.greenparty.org.uk/convention2012/policy/housing">Housing</a>.</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-10-29 15:53:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/11/15/convention-votes-for-economic-democracy-and-housing-justice/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ New National Committee Elected ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/28/new-national-committee-elected/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Last weekend at our annual Convention members voted for a new National Committee. The results are as follows:</p>
<p><strong>Female co-chair:</strong> Ash Haynes</p>
<p><strong>Male co-chair:</strong> Sam Coates</p>
<p><strong>Treasurer:</strong> Charlene Conception</p>
<p><strong>Non-portfolio positions:</strong></p>
<p>Lisa Camps</p>
<p>Juliette Daigre</p>
<p>Robert Eagleton</p>
<p>Ellie Ferguson</p>
<p>Siobhan MacMahon</p>
<p>Rustam Majainah</p>
<p>Thanks to everyone who stood and congratulations to those elected.</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-10-28 11:28:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/28/new-national-committee-elected/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Young Greens Convention ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/05/young-greens-convention/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p><span>Every year the youth wing of the Green Party host their annual convention. This year we can expect a talk and discussion with the new leader of the party, Natalie Bennett.<br /> <br /> Entry to convention is free!<br /> </span></p>
<p><span><span>REGISTRATION IS NOW OPEN. Please make sure you fill in this form!<br /> <br /> <a href="https://docs.google.com/a/younggreens.org.uk/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dHNGbFFBdXNRODlTOUlxalU1R0FvTnc6MQ#gid=0" rel="nofollow nofollow" target="_blank"><span>https://docs.google.com/a/</span><span>younggreens.org.uk/</span><span>spreadsheet/</span><span>viewform?formkey=dHNGbFFBdX</span><span>NRODlTOUlxalU1R0FvTnc6MQ#g</span>id=0</a></span></span></p>
<p><span><br /> More information about exact fringes, events and socials yet to come, but please spread this event around and post here if you have any questions or ideas for fringes, or contact;<br /> <br /> Jack Parker (events officer)<br /> jackparker1991@aol.com</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-10-05 17:57:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/05/young-greens-convention/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Green Party calls for amnesty for students of London Metropolitan University ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/04/amnesty-for-students/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>The Green Party is opposed to the action of the UK Border Agency in removing the right of London Metropolitan University to accept foreign students.</p>
<p>Sam Coates, Young Greens co-chair said:<br /><br />“The Government’s action in preventing London Metropolitan University from taking foreign students will rebound negatively upon the UK’s universities. Because the Government has made getting a visa far more difficult by creating a demanding process, foreign student visa applications have already dropped 21% June 2011-June 2012.<br /><br />"London Met’s 2700 foreign students are now struggling to find places to start or to continue studying. The Government has made Universities very dependent upon foreign student income: it is currently about 32% of University income from fees.<br /><br />“The Green Party supports the calls for an amnesty for the students affected.<br /><br />“This case is already being reported abroad. The Green Party is concerned about the viability of courses and the impact upon jobs in universities sector. Universities have neither the staff nor the resources to act as miniature versions of the UK Border Agency, which is constantly changing rules it uses. The UK should aspire to be a world leader in education, yet this atrocious move will severely damage our international reputation."</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-10-04 16:16:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2012/10/04/amnesty-for-students/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Young Greens Convention - Register now ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/20/young-greens-convention-register-now/</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>Every year the youth wing of the Green Party host their annual convention. This year we can expect a talk and discussion with the new leader of the party, Natalie Bennett.</p>
<p>Entry to convention is free!</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/a/younggreens.org.uk/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dHNGbFFBdXNRODlTOUlxalU1R0FvTnc6MQ#gid=0">REGISTRATION IS NOW OPEN</a>. Please make sure you <a href="https://docs.google.com/a/younggreens.org.uk/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dHNGbFFBdXNRODlTOUlxalU1R0FvTnc6MQ#gid=0">fill in this form</a>!</p>
<p>More information about exact fringes, events and socials yet to come, but please spread this event around and don't forget to join the <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/390873164306439/?ref=ts&amp;fref=ts.">facebook</a> event</p>
<p>If you have any questions or ideas for fringes, please contact Jack Parker (events officer) - jackparker1991@aol.com</p> ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2012-10-02 11:27:00</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/2013/03/20/young-greens-convention-register-now/</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Duplicate of Police spend more on press officers, as boroughs face cuts ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/duplicate-of-police-spend-more-on-press-officers,-as-boroughs-face-cuts.html</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>
The Green Party's Home Affairs spokesperson and member of the Metropolitan Police Authority, Jenny Jones AM, questioned the London Mayor today about why the number of Met Police press officers had increased since 2007/08, along with a 20% jump in their publicity budget. This has happened despite a 2008 manifesto pledge that Boris Johnson made to spend more on frontline police by reducing the number of staff in the directorate of public affairs from 74 to 50 and to halve the Metropolitan Police publicity budget.
</p>
<p>
The Mayor responded to Jenny at today's Mayor's Question Time by saying that he &quot;would look at the figures&quot; and she had &quot;got a result&quot;.
</p>
<p>
Jenny Jones said:<br />
<br />
&quot;The Mayor promised to dramatically cut down the number of Met Police press staff and to slash the publicity budget, but both have risen since he was elected. It is ridiculous that the Met is spending more money on its image, whilst cutting borough police budgets by 5% year after year. The Mayor promised to increase frontline police, but one of the main impacts of his policies next year will be to cut the frontline traffic police section by 20 officers, 5 PCSOs and 5 staff. This is the opposite of what Londoners were promised.&quot; <br />
<br />
<strong>Notes to editors</strong><br />
<br />
Police and press officers<br />
<br />
Q: Should Londoners hold you to account on you manifesto commitment to spend less on MPS press officers and more on police officers?
</p>
<p>
Manifesto commitment: <br />
&quot;We need to spend less on press officers, and more on police officers. We need to redirect more resources to frontline policing.&quot;(Making London Safer, p5)
</p>
<p>
&quot;I will release funds that Ken Livingstone has earmarked for MPA advertising and press officers to be spent on approximately 50 extra fully-warranted British Transport Police Officers to patrol the worst stations in outer London.&quot;(Making London Safer, p6)<br />
<br />
&quot;By reducing the number of press staff to 50 and halving publicity spend we will redirect &pound;3.1 million from marketing and spin to frontline policing.&quot; (Making London Safer, p.16)
</p>
<p>
Facts:<br />
MPS Dept of Public Affairs:<br />
Spending<br />
07/08 outturn- &pound;5.7m<br />
10/11 budget - &pound;6.8m (nearly 20% increase)<br />
Staffing<br />
07/08 - 73<br />
10/11 - 74<br />
<br />
Instead of taking money for transport police from public affairs/press officers Mayor is taking money from<br />
*	Borough Command budgets <br />
*	Traffic Unit budget (cut by 10%)<br />
*	Income raised from fines levied on uninsured drivers<br />
<br />
</p>
 ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2010-03-18 13:33:41</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/duplicate-of-police-spend-more-on-press-officers,-as-boroughs-face-cuts.html</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
 <item>  
<title><![CDATA[ Police spend more on press officers, as boroughs face cuts ]]></title>  
<link>http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/police-spend-more-on-press-officers,-as-boroughs-face-cuts.html</link>  
<description><![CDATA[ <p>
The Green Party's Home Affairs spokesperson and member of the Metropolitan Police Authority, Jenny Jones AM, questioned the London Mayor today about why the number of Met Police press officers had increased since 2007/08, along with a 20% jump in their publicity budget. This has happened despite a 2008 manifesto pledge that Boris Johnson made to spend more on frontline police by reducing the number of staff in the directorate of public affairs from 74 to 50 and to halve the Metropolitan Police publicity budget.
</p>
<p>
The Mayor responded to Jenny at today's Mayor's Question Time by saying that he &quot;would look at the figures&quot; and she had &quot;got a result&quot;.
</p>
<p>
Jenny Jones said:<br />
<br />
&quot;The Mayor promised to dramatically cut down the number of Met Police press staff and to slash the publicity budget, but both have risen since he was elected. It is ridiculous that the Met is spending more money on its image, whilst cutting borough police budgets by 5% year after year. The Mayor promised to increase frontline police, but one of the main impacts of his policies next year will be to cut the frontline traffic police section by 20 officers, 5 PCSOs and 5 staff. This is the opposite of what Londoners were promised.&quot; <br />
<br />
<strong>Notes to editors</strong><br />
<br />
Police and press officers<br />
<br />
Q: Should Londoners hold you to account on you manifesto commitment to spend less on MPS press officers and more on police officers?
</p>
<p>
Manifesto commitment: <br />
&quot;We need to spend less on press officers, and more on police officers. We need to redirect more resources to frontline policing.&quot;(Making London Safer, p5)
</p>
<p>
&quot;I will release funds that Ken Livingstone has earmarked for MPA advertising and press officers to be spent on approximately 50 extra fully-warranted British Transport Police Officers to patrol the worst stations in outer London.&quot;(Making London Safer, p6)<br />
<br />
&quot;By reducing the number of press staff to 50 and halving publicity spend we will redirect &pound;3.1 million from marketing and spin to frontline policing.&quot; (Making London Safer, p.16)
</p>
<p>
Facts:<br />
MPS Dept of Public Affairs:<br />
Spending<br />
07/08 outturn- &pound;5.7m<br />
10/11 budget - &pound;6.8m (nearly 20% increase)<br />
Staffing<br />
07/08 - 73<br />
10/11 - 74<br />
<br />
Instead of taking money for transport police from public affairs/press officers Mayor is taking money from<br />
*	Borough Command budgets <br />
*	Traffic Unit budget (cut by 10%)<br />
*	Income raised from fines levied on uninsured drivers<br />
<br />
</p>
 ]]></description>  
<pubDate>2010-03-18 13:20:23</pubDate>  
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://younggreen.greenparty.org.uk/news/police-spend-more-on-press-officers,-as-boroughs-face-cuts.html</guid>  
<dc:creator>Young Green Party</dc:creator>   
</item> 
</channel>
</rss>